Before we can use landmark measurements of the objects
自分のまわりにあるオブジェクトの目印の 測量を使用して
around us to update the belief of our position,
自分がいる大体の位置を 更新する前に
we'll have to solve the data association problem.
データ関連の問題を 解決する必要があります
Data association is the problem of matching
データの関連付けは 地図の目印などの
landmark measurements to objects in the real world,
実世界のオブジェクトに 目印の測量を一致させることの
like map landmarks.
問題です
Let's look at an example to show why data association is
データの関連付けが どうしてそんなに重要なのか
so important.
を示す例を見ていきましょう
We can assume that we're confident that we
こことここに 2 つの ライダーセンサーがあるので
have two lidar sensor measurements, here and here.
これらの２つの測定のどちらがこの岩に対応しますか？
Which of these two measurements corresponds to this rock?
このセンサーのどちらの測量が この石に対応しているのでしょうか?
If we pick the top measurement, then we
上側の測量を 選んだ場合 自動車の
will estimate that the true position of the car
実際の位置は 実はここであると
is actually here.
想定します
Remember that for localization, when sensor measurements--
ローカライゼーションの場合 センサーが測定するとき
or what we actually see--
または実際に見えるものが--
matches to map landmarks--
地図の目印と一致する--
what we expect to see--
見ようとしているもの--
this must be the true position of the car.
これが実際の自動車の 位置になるはずということを覚えておいてください
However, if we pick the bottom measurement,
ただし 下側の測量を 選んだ場合 自動車の
then we will estimate that the true position of the car
実際の位置は 実はここであると
is here.
想定します
So how do we pick the right measurement?
よって どうやって正しい測量 を選ぶのでしょうか?
For the self-driving car, you might
自動運転車の場合 目印が青
have a map with landmarks, shown in blue, and lidar
ライダー測量がオレンジで 示された地図を
measurements, shown in orange.
持っているかもしれません
Oftentimes, you have some map landmarks
地図に目印が いくつかあり
that have multiple lidar measurements that
それが複数のライバー測量をして それに対応していることが
could correspond to it.
よくあります
To pick the right correspondents,
正しく対応しているのを 選ぶには
we can use a very simple technique called
最近傍法 という とてもシンプルなテクニックを
nearest neighbor.
使うことができます
In this method, simply take the closest measurement
この方法では 丸で囲んだ地図の目印やライダー測量のように
as the correct correspondents, like the circled map landmark
一番近い測量を 正しく対応しているものとして
and lidar measurement.
選びます
Here, the red circles represent the associations
ここで 赤い丸は 地図の目印と
between the map landmarks and lidar measurements
最近傍法 を使って選んだ ライダー測量間の
that we would pick using nearest neighbor.
関連性を 示しています
Now, I want you to use your understanding of the nearest
では 最近傍法の
neighbor technique to answer a conceptual question
知識を利用して その優れている点と弱点についての
about its strengths and weaknesses.
概念的な質問に 答えてください